# Alessandro **Pezzato**

Trebaseleghe, PD, Italy

💌 alessandro@pezzato.net | 👑 1986 | 😭 alepez.dev | 🖸 alepez | 😽 alepez | 🗟 alessandro-pezzato | 🛅 alessandropezzato

"Learn. Code. Teach. Repeat."

## Summary.

With over 18 years of professional software development experience and a passion for programming that began at the age of 11, I bring a wealth of expertise to the table.

Specializing in C++ since 2007, I have consistently delivered high-quality solutions throughout my career.

I offer consulting, training, and software development services to companies, specializing in C, C++, Rust, Linux, and technologies for embedded and IoT systems.

Since 2014, I have been working as an independent software developer, taking on various projects.

In addition to my development work, I have also taken on the role of a trainer, sharing my knowledge and expertise with other developers to help them enhance their skills.

I have organized and conducted numerous C++ and Rust courses, providing comprehensive training on best practices and various software development methodologies.

As both a developer and a trainer, I am committed to staying up-to-date with the latest industry trends and technologies, ensuring that I can provide the most relevant and valuable guidance to my clients and students.

# Work Experience (as independent consultant) \_\_\_\_\_

Bluewind S.r.l.

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT, TRAINER

- · Implemented drivers and firmware for various safety critical embedded systems for automotive, marine and and industrial products. Languages: C. C++. Rust.
- Organized C++ and Rust courses for about ten developers.

Texa S.p.A. Monastier, Italy

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT, TRAINER

2014 - Present

- Developed C++ communication libraries (both embedded and server side) for an IoT automotive project to handle real-time remote diagnostic data of about 500 thousands vehicles.
- Organized multiple C++ courses between 2015 and 2022, a total of about 150 hours and 40 developers.

#### Spring Tech Innovations S.r.l.

Limena, Italy

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT

2022

• Developed C++ software for an home automation and alarm system.

**Ferrous Systems GmbH** 

• Developed Rust compiler tests for Ferrocene qualified toolchain.

MERMEC S.p.A.

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT

Morgano, Italy

Berlin, Germany

• Developed C++ and C# software for surface inspection of steel products.

ASTRA Vacht S.r.l.

2020 - 2022

2015 - 2022

2021

Monfalcone, Italy

DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT

• Developed C++ software for sailboat real-time performance analysis.

Qascom S.r.l. Bassano del Grappa, Italy

TRAINER

Organized a 45 hours C++ course for 20 developers.

Salvagnini S.p.A. Sarego, Italy

2019 - 2020 TRAINER

- Organized a course on modern C++ and Test Driven Development, for a total of 24 hours and 10 developers.
- Organized a course on Test Driven Development for C and C++, for a total of 24 hours and 10 developers.

**Ubilot S.r.l.**Bassano del Grappa, Italy

Developer, Consultant 2019

• Developed C++ and C# software.

Adatta S.r.l. Padova, Italy

Trainer 2018

Coached a junior C++ developer.

Carel S.p.A. Brugine, Italy

2014 - 2018)

**DEVELOPER, CONSULTANT**• Developed C++ software and C Linux drivers for HVAC products.

GM Trading srls

Borgoricco, Italy

DEVELOPER 2014 - 2018

• Developed (JavaScript) UI of an e-commerce website

# Work Experience (employee)

Vimage S.r.l. Mirano, Italy

LEAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jul 2007 - Jul 2014

- Coordinated and mentored the R&D team of up to 5 developers.
- Worked on different projects for museums, stores and events. Most projects involved interactive projections, touchscreens, touchless sensors and computer vision.
- Developed company's core C++ libraries for 2d and 3d games.
- Developed a company Linux distribution based on Gentoo Linux.

Nasch S.r.l. Padova, Italy

 Web Developer
 Oct 2005 - Apr 2007

- Developed local companies websites (PHP and JavaScript).
- Developed a web tv platform (Flash and ActionScript 3)

### Education

Liceo Scientifico E. Majorana Mirano, Italy

SCIENTIFIC HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA WITH A SPECIALIZATION IN THE NATIONAL INFORMATICS PLAN (P.N.I.) 2001 - 2005

Università di Padova Padua, Italy

MECHANICAL ENGINEERING (INCOMPLETE) 2005 - 2006

Università Ca' Foscari Venezia Venice, Italy

Business Administration (Incomplete) 2006 - 2008

Skills

**Programming tools and techniques** Git, gdb, Docker, NeoVim, CLion, TDD

**Programming Languages** C++, C, Rust, JavaScript, Python, Haskell, C#, Bash

Languages Italian, English